Guide to the Trent Collection of Whitmaniana, 1841-1992, bulk 1845-1849, 1854-1857, and 1864-1892
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Trent Collection of Whitmaniana 1841-1992, bulk 1845-1849, 1854-1857, and 1864-1892
Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892
40 linear feet
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Collection includes correspondence separated into two subseries: "Letters To or About Walt Whitman," and "Letters From or By Walt Whitman." Most of Whitman's letters in the collection were written between 1880 and 1891. Letters include those written to and from friends, family members, editors, publishers, and soldiers Whitman met in and around Washington, D. C. during the Civil War. The Clippings Series includes both large groups of clippings collected and annotated by Whitman, and clippings Whitman took from complete or nearly complete articles. Also included are manuscripts and printed materials about or relating to Whitman, most of which date between the late nineteenth century and the end of World War II. There are portraits, etchings, engravings, and sketches both of Whitman and of other subjects. A Writings Series contains manuscript and printed versions of poetry and prose dating from Whitman's career in journalism up through the mid-1940s. It is divided into seven subseries: Manuscript Poems (1855-1882 and n.d.); Manuscript Prose (1852-1891 and n.d.); Proofs (1874-1891 and n.d.); Poems Set to Music (1901-1933); Books and Periodicals Containing Contributions by Whitman (1841-1924); Editions of Whitman's Writings (1855-1944); and Bibliographies and Catalogs (1922-1943).
RL.02034
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The bulk of Duke University's Walt Whitman holdings were acquired through a series of substantial donations made by Dr. and Mrs. Josiah C. Trent, from whom the Trent Collection of Whitmaniana takes its name. Much of the Trent material was originally gathered by Richard Maurice Bucke, Whitman's friend and literary executor, who sold manuscript versions of his biography of Whitman, along with his collection of unpublished letters and Whitman's personal papers and books, in London in 1935. The next year, Jacob Schwartz offered for sale in New York a large portion of the Whitman holdings that had belonged to Bucke, and many of the items listed in the catalogue of this sale were a part of the original donation made to Duke by Dr. and Mrs. Trent in 1942. The Trent family made several important additions to their initial bequest in the years following the establishment of the collection, but Duke University does not expect its Whitman manuscript holdings to expand at any time in the near future.
Biographical Note
1819 May 31 Born Walter Whitman in West Hills, Huntington Township, N.Y. to Walter and Louisa (VanVelsor) Whitman
1823 Whitman family moved to Brooklyn
1825-1830 Attended Brooklyn public schools
1830-1831 Worked as office boy for lawyer and doctor
1831-1832 Printing apprentice for Long Island Patriot
1832-1835 Worked as compositor for Long Island Star
1836-1838 Taught school on Long Island
1838-1839 Worked on two newspapers, Long Islander and Long Island Democrat
1840 Campaigned for Martin Van Buren
1840-1841 Taught school on Long Island
1841 Moved to New York City; worked as compositor for The New World
1842-1845 Worked for and contributed to various newspapers in New York City
1845-1846 Returned to Brooklyn and worked for Evening Star
1846-1848 Edited Brooklyn's Daily Eagle
1848 Left Daily Eagle, went to New Orleans to edit Daily Crescent. Resigned and returned to Brooklyn.
1848-1849 Founded and edited Weekly Freeman, a "free-soil" newspaper
1849-1854 Operated printing office, bookstore, and house building business and did freelance journalism
1855 Copyrighted first edition of Leaves of Grass
1855-1856 Wrote for Life Illustrated; published second edition of Leaves of Grass
1857-1860 Edited Brooklyn Daily Times
1860 Published third edition of Leaves of Grass
1861-1862 Wrote freelance journalism; visited soldiers in New York Hospital; visited wounded brother in Fredericksburg
1863-1864 Moved to Washington, D.C.; worked as clerk in Army Paymaster's Office; visited military hospitals; returned to Brooklyn for 6 months in 1864
1865 Returned to Washington, D.C. and worked as clerk in Indian Bureau of Department of the Interior; began and suspended printing of Drum-Taps; discharged by Secretary James Harlan for writing "obscene" poetry; transferred to clerkship in Attorney General's Office; again published Drum-Taps and Sequel; began relationship with Peter Doyle
1866 William D. O'Connor published The Good Gray Poet, a defense co-written by Whitman in response to Whitman's firing by Harlan
1867 4th edition of Leaves of Grass published
1868 Poems of Walt Whitman published in London
1870 5th edition of Leaves of Grass published
1873 Suffered paralytic stroke; mother died on May 23rd; moved in with brother George in Camden, N.J.
1874 Discharged from his position in Washington, D.C.
1876 Published Centennial edition of Leaves of Grass and Two Rivulets, and Memoranda During the War; befriended Harry Stafford
1879 Gave first Lincoln lecture in New York
1882 Publicity concerning the suppression of Leaves of Grass in Boston resulted in unprecedented sales
1888 Suffered a second paralytic stroke; made will naming Richard Maurice Bucke, Thomas Harned, and Horace Traubel literary executors
1889 70th birthday commemorated in Camden's Compliment to Walt Whitman
1892 Died March 26th; buried in Harleigh Cemetery, Camden, N.J.
Collection Overview
The Trent Collection of Whitmaniana incorporates material spanning the dates 1841-1947, with the bulk of the material dating from 1845-1849, 1854-1857, and 1864-1892. The virtual reorganization of the collection, based upon that devised by Ellen F. Frey in A Bibliography of Walt Whitman (Port Washington, NY: Kennikat Press, 1945), divides it into six series: Correspondence, Writings, Clippings, Material About or Relating to Whitman, Portraits, and Miscellany.
Correspondence is separated into two subseries: "Letters To or About Walt Whitman," and "Letters From or By Walt Whitman." Most of Whitman's letters in the collection were written between 1880 and 1891. The Clippings Series lists both large groups of clippings collected and annotated by Whitman, and clippings Whitman took from complete or nearly complete articles. Whenever possible, these have been dated according to the periodical in which the articles originally appeared. Material About or Relating to Whitman is comprised of four subseries that catalog manuscript versions of Richard Maurice Bucke's biography of Whitman, other manuscript material written mostly by Whitman's friends, and books, pamphlets, and periodicals about Whitman's life and work, most of which date between the late nineteenth century and the end of World War II. The Portraits Series includes formal photographic and painted portraits, etchings, engravings, and sketches, both of Whitman and of other subjects, including George Sand, Oliver Wendell Holmes, and Whitman's brother George. The Miscellany consists of ephemera related to Whitman's life and career as a poet. Two scrapbooks, a leaflet of receipts, book wrappers for the first edition of Leaves of Grass, and documents relating to the Whitman fund are listed among this series' eclectic contents.
By far the largest series in the collection, the Writings Series contains manuscript and printed versions of poetry and prose dating from Whitman's career in journalism up through the mid-1940s. It is divided into seven subseries: Manuscript Poems (1855-1882 and undated); Manuscript Prose (1852-1891 and undated); Proofs (1874-1891 and undated); Poems Set to Music (1901-1933); Books and Periodicals Containing Contributions by Whitman (1841-1924); Editions of Whitman's Writings (1855-1944); and Bibliographies and Catalogs (1922-1943). The first subseries, "Manuscript Poems," is further subdivided into categories intended to define three separate levels of poetic composition: manuscript versions of poems that appear in at least one edition of Leaves of Grass, manuscript versions of poems not published in Leaves of Grass, and verse fragments and outlines. The researcher is advised to consult the NYU Collected Writings of Walt Whitman, particularly Harold W. Blodgett and Sculley Bradley, eds., Leaves of Grass: A Comprehensive Reader's Edition (New York: NYUP, 1965), pp. 585-706, for publication of previously uncollected material. Although older, Oscar Lovell Triggs, ed., Leaves of Grass by Walt Whitman, vol. 3 of 10 (New York: G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1902) and Clarence Gohdes and Rollo G. Silver, eds., Faint Clews and Indirections: Manuscripts of Walt Whitman and His Family (Durham, NC: Duke UP, 1949) are also helpful, the former particularly when used alongside Frey's Bibliography.
The Manuscript Prose Subseries in the Writings Series is further divided into seven categories. The first three are comprised of manuscript versions of stories, prefaces, and essays and lectures, respectively. Four less distinct subheadings follow. "Notes on Literature" represents an almost exact transliteration of Frey's category of the same name, however it should be noted that this category does not, at the time of writing, list all of Trent's holdings in Whitman's literary-critical manuscripts. Some literary criticism is contained in "Autobiographical Manuscripts" and "Whitman on His Own Writings," along with more purely impressionistic self-reflection. "Miscellany" should also be consulted, as it brings together in an unsystematic way Whitman's notes on travel, reading, and education as well as a scattering of notes on poetry and different forms of literary production.
The last five subseries of the Writings Series bring together various published versions of Whitman's writing. Annotated proofs of his poetry and prose are identified in the finding aid, and cross-references are included between the Proofs Subseries and the Books and Periodicals Containing Contributions by Whitman Subseries in instances where the Trent Collection lists both a proof and a published version of a poem or article among its headings. The Books and Periodicals Containing Contributions by Whitman Subseries and the Bibliographies and Catalogs Subseries are nearly comprehensive surveys of pre-World War II editions of Whitman's writing and of Whitman bibliographies. The Poems Set to Music Subseries catalogs a number of Whitman's poems that were given musical settings, mostly in the first two decades of the twentieth century. See Bella C. Landauer, Leaves of Music by Walt Whitman, call number Trent I-9, for full bibliographic information on these pieces.
Many published works by and about Walt Whitman and housed in the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library have been cataloged individually. These can be found by searching the Duke online catalog.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Trent, Josiah C. (Josiah Charles), 1914-; Bucke, Richard Maurice, 1837-1902; Frey, Ellen Frances; Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892; Sand, George, 1804-1876; Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1809-1894; Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892. Leaves of grass; American literature -- 19th century; Poets, American -- 19th century; Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892; Whitman, Walt, 1819-1892—Manuscripts; Poets, American -- 19th century
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series, 1860-1922 and undated
  Letters to and from friends, family members, editors, publishers, and soldiers Whitman met during his time as a nurse in military hospitals in and around Washington, D. C. primarily during the Civil War. However, correspondence is dated both during and after the war.
  - Correspondence to or About Whitman Subseries, 1860-1922 and undated (bulk 1860-1892)
    Includes letters from friends, family members, and soldiers. Many of the letters have been bound into various scrapbooks and collections of other Whitman papers, and it is advisable to consult the reference archivist with regard to the physical provenance of the material before requesting correspondence in bulk. Listed alphabetically by author.
    - Arens, Egmont: To Horace Traubel, 1915 April 2 (Box II-7C)
    - Bucke, Richard Maurice: To Reuben Farwell (Typescript), 1898 Oct. 14 (Box III [display])
    - Bucke, Richard Maurice: To W. D. O'Connor, 1880 July 1 (Box III-5A)
    - Bucke, Richard Maurice: To Walt Whitman, 1888 Aug. 17
    - Bucke, Richard Maurice: To Walt Whitman, 1889 Jan. 18
    - Bucke, Richard Maurice: To Editor of Scribner's Monthly, undated (Box III-5B)
    - Burroughs, Julian: To Bayard Wyman, undated (Box II-9D)
    - Caffin, Charles H.: To Horace Traubel, 1915 May 19 (Box II-7C)
    - Caffin, Charles H.: To Horace Traubel, 1916 May 29
    - Chainey, George: To W. D. O'Connor, 1882 July 11 (Box III-5B)
    - Chainey, George: To W. D. O'Connor, 1882 July 30
    - Davenport, William E.: To Dr. William Roscoe Thayer, 1921 Nov. 26 (Box III-5B)
    - Davenport, William E.: To Dr. William Roscoe Thayer, 1922 Jan. 8
    - Davenport, William E.: To Dr. William Roscoe Thayer, 1922 Apr. 10
    - Doyle, Peter: To Walt Whitman 1868 Sept. 21 (Box III-5B)
    - Farwell, Reuben: To Walt Whitman, 1864 Apr. 30 (Box III-5 [III display])
    - Farwell, Reuben: To Walt Whitman, 1864 May 5
    - Farwell, Reuben: To Walt Whitman, 1864 May 10
    - Farwell, Reuben: To Walt Whitman, 1864 June 8
    - Farwell, Reuben: To Walt Whitman, 1864 Oct. 2
    - Farwell, Reuben: To Walt Whitman, 1864 Nov. 7
    - Farwell, Reuben: To Walt Whitman, 1864 Nov. 21
    - Farwell, Reuben: To Walt Whitman, [1865?] June 16
    - Farwell, Reuben: To Walt Whitman, 1875 Feb. 11
    - Farwell, Reuben: To Walt Whitman, 1875 Mar. 5
    - Farwell, Reuben: To Walt Whitman, 1875 Aug. 16
    - Fournier, Paul: To Horace Traubel, 1908 April 6 (Box II-7C)
    - Hay, John: To "Charlie," 1861 Aug. 2
    - Heyde, Charles L.: To Louisa Whitman, 1868 Nov. 24 (Box III-5B)
    - Heyde, Charles L.: To Louisa Whitman, 1868 Dec.
    - Heyde, Charles L.: To Louisa Whitman, 1852-1873 (Box III-5A)
    - Heyde, Charles L.: To Walt Whitman, 1860-1892
    - Heyde, Hannah Whitman: To Louisa Whitman, undated (Box III-5B)
    - Heyde, Hannah Whitman: To Louisa Whitman, undated (Box III-5A)
    - Heyde, Hannah Whitman: To Walt Whitman, undated
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell: To unidentified recipient, 1890 Feb. 18 (Box III-5B: [II display])
    - Hugo, Victor: To Arthur Monnanteuil, 1868 July 7 (Box III-5B)
    - Partridge, William Ordway: To Horace Traubel, 1897 January 17 (Box II-7C)
    - Partridge, William Ordway: To Horace Traubel, 1897 January 21
    - Partridge, William Ordway: To Horace Traubel, 1897 December 28
    - Price, Abby H.: To Louisa Whitman, undated (Box III-5B)
    - Price, Helen E.: To Louisa Whitman, 1872 Oct. 13 (Box III-5B)
    - Price, Helen E.: To Louisa Whitman, 1872 Nov. 24
    - Price, Helen E.: To Louisa Whitman, 1873 Jan. 1
    - Price, Helen E.: To Louisa Whitman, 1873 Jan. 31
    - Price, Helen E.: To Louisa Whitman, 1873 Feb. 9
    - Price, Helen E.: To Louisa Whitman, [1873?], Saturday
    - Price, Helen E.: To Louisa Whitman, 1873 Mar. 27
    - Stansberry, William: To Walt Whitman, 1873 Dec. 9 (Box II-9C)
    - Stansberry, William: To Walt Whitman, 1874 May 12
    - Stansberry, William: To Walt Whitman, 1874 June 28
    - Stansberry, William: To Walt Whitman, 1875 July 21
    - Stansberry, William: To Walt Whitman from Stansberry's wife, 1874 July 15
    - Van Nostrand, Mary Whitman: To Louisa Whitman, [1875?] Feb. 16 (Box III-5B)
    - Van Nostrand, Mary Whitman: To Walt Whitman, 1875 Feb. 16
    - Walkowitz, Abraham: To Horace Traubel, 1917 April 1 (Box II-7C)
    - Whitman, George: To Louisa Whitman, 1861-1865 (Box III-5C)
    - Whitman, George: To Walt Whitman, 1861-1865
    - Whitman, George: To Thomas Jefferson Whitman, undated
    - Whitman, Louisa: To Walt Whitman, 1860-1868 (Box III-5E)
    - Whitman, Louisa: To Walt Whitman, 1868-1873 (Box III-5F)
    - Whitman, Louisa: Typescript transcription of letters (Box III-5D)
    - Whitman, Thomas Jefferson: To Walt Whitman, undated (Box III-5C)
    - Williams, F. H.: To Horace Traubel, 1897 December 26 (Box II-7C)
    - Young, Art: To Horace Traubel, 1917 January 4 (Box II-7C)
  - Correspondence from or by Whitman Subseries, 1861-1891
    Contains letters by friends and family members, editors, publishers, and soldiers. As with the Correspondence to or about Whitman Subseries, many letters in this subseries are bound with other material and the reference archivist should be contacted before correspondence is requested in bulk. Most of Whitman's letters in the Trent Collection date from 1880 to 1891. See also transcribed correspondence from or by Whitman in the Bliss Perry Whitman Collection in the Miscellany Series. Listed alphabetically by recipient.
    - Bucke, Richard Maurice: 1892 Jan. 27 (Box II-9A)
    - Burroughs, John: 1868 Oct. 22 [?] (Box II-9C)
    - Burroughs, John: 1878 July 5 (Box III-1)
    - Burroughs, John: 1885 June 23 (Box II-9A)
    - Burroughs, John and Ursula: 1875 Mar. 2 (Box II-9D)
    - Carpenter, Edward: 1877 Oct. 5 (Box II-9D)
    - Carpenter, Edward: 1877 Nov. 27 (Box II-9A)
    - Carpenter, Edward: 1885 Aug. 5 (Box II-9D)
    - Contemporary Club, Executive Committee: 1888 Feb. 15 (Box II-9A)
    - Cox, George: 1887 June 14 (Box II-9A)
    - Dowden, Edward: 1876 Mar. 4 (Box II-9D)
    - Doyle, Peter: 1877 July 2 (Box II-9A)
    - Doyle, Peter: 1880 July 24
    - Doyle, Peter: Dec. 20
    - Edmunds, J. M., Postmaster: Nov. 17 (Box II-9B)
    - Eldridge, Charley: 1873 June 23 (Box II-9A)
    - Eldridge, Charley: 1873 July 7
    - Eldridge, Charley: 1884 May 7
    - Harper's Magazine: To Editor, 1873 Nov. 2 (Box II-9A)
    - Harper's Magazine: To Foreman in the Composing Room, 1873 Dec. 15
    - Johnson, R. U.: 1884 Aug. 4
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1881 Dec. 21 (Box I-8C)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1886 Aug. 5
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 Feb. 21
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 Mar. 1
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 June 13
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 July 13
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 Sept. 14
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 Oct. 4 (Box II-9A)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1887 Nov. 17 (Box I-8C)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1888 January 10
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1888 Mar. 26
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1888 May 7
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1888 Sept. 1
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1888 Oct. 19
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1889 Jan. 5
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1889 Feb. 14 (Box II-9A)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1889 Oct. 13
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1889 Oct. 17
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 Jan. 27
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 Feb. 10
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 Apr. 11
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 Apr. 11
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 June 18 (Box II-9D)
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 Aug. 4
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1890 Dec. 29
    - Kennedy, William Sloane: 1881-1889 (Box I-8C)
    - "McGuire": 1872 May 2 (Box II-9D)
    - Nicholson, Tommy: 1880 Dec. 17 (Box II-9C)
    - Nicholson, Tommy: 1881 Mar. 17
    - Nicholson, Tommy: 1883 Sept. 5
    - O'Connor, William D.: 1868 Oct. 4 (Box II-9C)
    - Rolleston, T. W. H.: 1880 Dec. 2 (Box I-4)
    - Rosetti, William: 1886 May 30 (Box III-8A)
    - Russell, Dr. LeBaron [?]: 1864 Feb. (Box II-9C)
    - Ryder, Jr., Anson: 1866 Dec. 14 (Box II-9C)
    - Stansberry, William: 1874 May 20 (Box II-9C)
    - Stilwell, Julia Elizabeth: 1863 Oct. 21 (Box II-9C)
    - Stoddart, J. M.: 1890 Apr. 24 (Box II-9D)
    - Swinton, John: 1865 Feb. 3 (Box II-9C)
    - Tilton, J. W.: 1889 Jan. 6 (Box II-9D)
    - Tottie, Oscar: July 26 (Box II-9C)
    - Trowbridge, J. T. [?]: 1870 [?] Sept. 24 (Box II-9D)
    - Trubner and Company: 1873 Dec. 21 (Box II-9C)
    - Trubner and Company: 1878 Oct. 1 [?] (Box II-9D)
    - Van Wyck, Samuel: 1879 May 28 (Box II-9D)
    - Waters, George: 1878 Nov. 10 (Box II-9D)
    - Whitman, George: 1861 July 12 (Box II-9C)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1866 June 26 (Box II-9B)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1866 June 29 (Box II-9D)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1867 Mar. 19 (Box II-9B)
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1867 Mar. 26
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1867 Apr. 16
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1867 Apr. 30
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1868 June 6
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1868 July 10
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1868 Aug. 24
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1868 Aug. 30
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1868 Nov. 24
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1872 Aug. 22
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1872 Aug. 27
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1872 Oct. 15
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1872 [?] Nov. 14
    - Whitman, Louisa: 1873 Jan. 17
    - Whitman, Thomas Jefferson: 1867 Apr. 29 (Box II-9C)
    - Wilkins, Edward: 1889 Dec. 31 (Box II-9B)
    - Wilkins, Edward: 1890 Mar. 20
    - Wilkins, Edward: 1890 Apr. 29
    - Wilkins, Edward: 1890 Dec. 24
    - Wilkins, Edward: 1891 Sept. 30
    - Letters to Unidentified Recipients: 1889 Oct. 7 (Box II-9D)
    - Letters to Unidentified Recipients: 1891 May 8
- Writings Series, 1841-1944 and undated
  Consists of manuscript drafts and revisions of Whitman's poetry and prose as well as proofs and published versions of his work from his early career in journalism up through the end of his life. The categorization of the manuscript material is necessarily inexact, and it is recommended that the researcher consult Ellen F. Frey's A Bibliography of Walt Whitman, Being a Catalog of the Trent Collection of Duke University, for detailed descriptions of the manuscript fragments. A copy of Frey's Bibliography is available from the reference staff upon request. The Writings Series also contains published versions of certain of Whitman's poems that were set to music by several different composers. For a comprehensive guide to these works, see Frey or see Bella C. Landauer, Leaves of Music by Walt Whitman, call number Trent I-9.
  - Manuscript Poems Subseries, ca. 1855 and undated
    Manuscript drafts and revisions of poems appearing in successive editions of Leaves of Grass and poems not published during Whitman's lifetime or not intended for Leaves of Grass.
    - Leaves of Grass
      Manuscript fragments are labeled "draft portions" if they constitute early drafts or revisions of a poem appearing in any of the editions of Leaves of Grass published during Whitman's lifetime. Fragments are labeled "draft outlines" if Frey suggests that they represent "ideas" treated in Leaves of Grass. Listed alphabetically by title.
      - By Blue Ontario's Shore (Autograph MS, draft of 1856 version, portion), Former call number: MS q 14 (Volume MS q 14)
      - Carols Closing Sixty-Nine (Autograph MS, title suggestions for Sands at Seventy), Former call number: MS q 20 (Volume MS q 20)
      - Faces (Autograph MS, draft portions), Former call number: MS q 9 (Volume MS q 9)
      - Great are the myths... (Autograph MS), Former call number: MS q 10 (Volume MS q 10)
      - You lusty and graceflu youth! (draft portions), Former call number: MS q 11 (Volume MS q 11)
      - In Paths Untrodden (Autograph MS, draft portions), Former call number: MS q 195 (Volume MS q 195)